Register of the Donald M. Brodie Miscellaneous Papers, 1919-1941
Hoover Institution Archives
Donald M. Brodie Miscellaneous Papers
1919-1941
82062
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope (0.9 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, maps, and printed matter, relating to the King-Crane report on mandates in Turkey, 1919, and to the Conference on American Relations with China, held in Baltimore, 1925.
Brodie, Donald M., 1890-1974
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1890, Aug. 31 Born, Cincinnati, Ohio
1911 A.B., Oberlin College
1915 M.A., Columbia University
1919 Member, American Committee to Negotiate Peace, Paris
1919 Secretary, American Commission on Mandates in Turkey
1920-1921 Secretary to American Minister, Peking, China
1922-1939 Financial Secretary to Charles R. Crane
1925-1955 Secretary-treasurer, Institute of Current World Affairs
1939-1946 Treasurer, China Institute in America
1947-1974 Treasurer, China Foundation
1974, Feb.3 Died, New York, N.Y.
Conference on American Relations with China (1925: Baltimore); Crane, Charles R.; Inter-Allied Commission on Mandates in Turkey.; China--Foreign relations--United States.; China.; Mandates--Middle East.; Middle East.; Turkey.; United States--Foreign relations--China.; United States--Foreign relations.; World War, 1914-1918--Territorial questions--Turkey.; World War, 1914-1918.
- THE INTERNATIONAL COMMISSION ON MANDATES IN TURKEY, AMERICAN SECTION (Box 1)
  General note
  Report, 1919. (Report by Charles R. Crane and Henry Churchill King). Typescript, correspondence, reports, fragments of drafts, related materials, arranged by physical form, 1919-1940.
- CONFERENCE ON AMERICAN RELATIONS WITH CHINA, Baltimore, Sept. 17-20, 1925 (Boxes 1-2)
  Preliminary papers, bulletins, correspondence, financial material, membership lists, arranged by physical form, 1925-1941.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1920-1931 (Box 2)
  Block prints, clippings, correspondence, printed matter, arranged alphabetically by topic.
- PHOTOGRAPHS
- THE INTERNATIONAL COMMISSION ON MANDATES IN TURKEY, AMERICAN SECTION.
  Report, 1919. (Report by Charles R. Crane and Henry Churchill King).
  - Section I. Report Upon Syria. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Typescript., Aug. 28, 1919
    - Fragments of drafts., n.d. (Folder 2)
    - Related materials. List of officials in Palestine and Syria; petitions and letters; report re conversations, with King Abdul Aziz Ibn Saud; "Summarized Statement of Significant Conclusions from the Petitions.", July 8, 1919-May 5, 1925 (Folder 3)
  - Section II. Report Upon Mesopotamia. Typescript., Aug. 28, 1919 (Folder 4)
  - Section III. Report Upon the Non-Arabic-Speaking Portions of the Former Ottomen Empire. Typescript., Aug. 28, 1919 (Folder 5)
  - Correspondence. Includes correspondence of C. R. Crane (Folder 6)
    - General., 1919-1940
    - Wilson, Woodrow., 1919-1922 (Folder 7)
  - Maps. Maps used in preparation of report. Compiled by Geographical Section, British General Staff., 1918 (Folder 8-9)
  - Miscellany. Biographies of commission members, memoranda re publication of King-Crane Report, press releases., 1919-1940 (Folder 10)
  - Material in Arabic. Petitions, invitations, miscellany., n.d. (Folder 11)
- CONFERENCE ON AMERICAN RELATIONS WITH CHINA, Baltimore, Sept. 17-20, 1925.
  - General. Proposed outline of program, announcement, preliminary report, comments., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Preliminary papers solicited by the Data Committee. Includes, Willoughby, W. W., "Extraterritoriality In China"; Eldridge, F. R., "Chinese Trade and Customs Control"; Lowrie, Gale S., "The Foreign Relations of China"; Warnhuis, A. L., "The Status of Missionaries in China"; Rogers, Walter S., "Communications"; Hodges, Charles, "Non-Political Factors Underlying the Chinese Problem"; Hodges, Charles, "Material Illustrative of Concession-Diplomacy in China"; Roots, L. H., "The Situation in China"; Kellogg, Frank B., "Speech About the Chinese Situation"; Stuart, J. Leighton, "The American Response to Chinese Opinion"., 1925 (Folder 13)
  - Bulletins. Nos. I-V, Sept. 1-15, 1925 (Folder 14)
  - Financial materials., 1925 (Folder 15)
  - Membership lists., 1925 (Folder 16)
  - Correspondence., 1925-1941 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1920-1931
  - The Anglo-Japanese Alliance. Memorandum, report., 1921 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - China (Folder 3)
    - Clippings and miscellaneous printed matter., 1925-1931
    - Reports and lectures., 1921 (Folder 4)
    - Prints., 1921 (Folder 5)
  - China Consortium. Agreement, minutes., 1921 (Folder 6)
  - Middle East. Clippings and printed matter., 1919-1926 (Folder 7)
  - Oberlin College. Special Committee of the Alumni Association. Reports, correspondence., 1926 (Folder 8)
  - Syria, visit by Charles R. Crane, Reports, correspondence., 1922 (Folder 9)
- PHOTOGRAPHS
  - 1 print of Viscount and Lady Allenby and miscellaneous prints (4 prints/1 envelope) (Envelope A)